From J.K. Rowling's wizarding world.
Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them is a fantasy,
adventure film directed by David Yates.
In 1926, Newt Scamander arrives at the Magical Congress of the United States of America with a
magically expanded briefcase, which houses a number of dangerous creatures and their habitats.
When the creatures escape from the briefcase, it sends the American wizarding authorities after Newt,
and threatens to strain even further the state of magical and non-magical relations.
Newt Scamander, played by Eddie Redmayne.
Porpentina 'Tina' Goldstein, played by Katherine Waterston.
Jacob Kowalski, played by Dan Fogler.
Queenie Goldstein, played by Alison Sudol.
Percival Graves, played by Colin Farrell.
Henry Shaw Sr., played by Jon Voight.
Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them is a 2016 fantasy
film directed by David Yates and written by J.
Rowling in her debut as a screenwriter.
It is the first instalment in the Fantastic Beasts film series and the ninth overall in the Wizarding
World franchise, serving as a spin-off of and prequel to the Harry Potter film series.
Newt Scamander's guide book of the same name—written by Rowling under the pen
name in 2001 for the charity Comic Relief—inspired the film.
It features an ensemble cast including Eddie Redmayne, Katherine Waterston, Dan Fogler, Alison Sudol,
Ezra Miller, Samantha Morton, Jon Voight, Carmen Ejogo, Ron Perlman and Colin Farrell.
A new Wizarding World film series was first announced in September 2013, two years after the
final Harry Potter film—Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 2—was released.
The following month, it was also announced that producer David Heyman and writer Steve Kloves,
who were both Potter film franchise veterans, will return in the new film series.
In August 2014, Warner Bros.
announced that Yates will direct at least one film of the planned trilogy, after rumors in
which Alfonso Cuarón would direct, of which he refuted three months earlier.
Filming took place from August 2015 to January 2016, at Warner Bros.
Studios Leavesden, and also on location in England.
Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them premiered at Alice Tully Hall in New York City on 10 November 2016, and was
released in theatres in the United States and in the United Kingdom on 18 November, by Warner Bros.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and emerged a commercial success, grossing $814
million worldwide, finishing its theatrical run as the eighth-highest-grossing film of 2016.
It received five nominations at the 70th British Academy Film Awards,
including Best British Film, and won for Best Production Design.
The film was also nominated for two awards at the 89th Academy Awards and won for Best
Costume Design, becoming the first Wizarding World film to win an Academy Award.
Two sequels—Fantastic Beasts: The Crimes of Grindelwald (2018) and Fantastic
Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore (2022)—have been released.
The film explores themes of witch, new york city,
robbery, escape, teleportation.